大家好
Hello everybody
谢谢你的光临
Thank you for , for coming
呃，是的
Uh , yes
所以，呃，让我们先道谢几句，让一切顺利进行
So , uh , let's just start off with a couple of thanks here to get it rolling
如果幻灯片有效，我们就开始吧
If the slides work , there we go
惊人的
Awesome
首先要感谢gdc对我的邀请
Firstly want to say thank you to gdc for inviting me
感谢独立峰会的组织者组织了这一切
thank you to the organizers of the indie summit for put this whole thing on
并找到如此出色的演讲者
And finding such great speakers
凯特·康彭的最后一篇演讲
Kate compon's talk last one
如果你看到了，那就太棒了
If you saw it , that was amazing
嗯
U um
所以我想打个招呼
So i want to say hi
我很重要
I'm matter
正如荷兰nhtv大学提到的，我是一名教授
I'm a professor , as mentioned from nhtv university in the netherlands
这是一个很棒的学习场所
It's an awesome place to study
如果您想了解欧洲的视频游戏
If you want to learn about video games in europe
你应该去那里
You should be going there
呃，我是一名游戏开发者
Uh , i'm a games developer
作为一名独立开发者，我经营了自己的名为 maizon 的公司七年
I ran my own company called maizon for seven years as an indie developer
呃
Uh
我为自己、为网络、为朋友制作游戏
I made games for myself , for the web , for friends
对于像第四频道的MTV 2这样的公司
And for companies like mtv two in channel four
呃，之后我就加入了ea和rebellion这样的人，呃
Uh , after that i went to join people like ea and rebellion , uh
为他们制作一些不同的作品
Working on a few different titles for them
我在哪里当作家
Where i was a writer
叙事设计师
Narrative designer
最终首席设计师
Lead designer in the very end
啊，在我去上班和做其他事情之前
Ah , before i went off to work and other things
最近我发布了他的片段
most recently i released fragments of him
去年，在 Xbox One 和 PC 上，我们与工作室里的几个很棒的人合作，名为 sassy bot
Last year on xbox one and pc in collaboration with an awesome couple of guys to studio called sassy bot
所以，呃，这是一种情感叙事游戏
So , uh , that's an emotional storytelling kind of game
呃，它被英国作家协会提名为电子游戏最佳编剧
Uh , it was nominated for the best writing in a video game by the writers guild of great britain
呃，既然我现在是正式会员了
Uh , where since i'm now a full member
还记得电子游戏委员会，呃
And remember the video game committee , uh
我还为叙事设计方面的人员提供咨询和培训
I also consult and trained people in narrative design
我做更多的事情
I do more stuff
我正在写关于天哪的书
I'm writing books about , oh god
反正
Anyway
我主要做游戏的事情，呃
I basically do game stuff , uh
我已经度过了整个成年生活
And i have done for my entire adult life
所以我今天要和你谈谈
So i'm gonna be talking to you today
呃，关于为什么理解故事结构对于游戏开发者来说是有用的技能
Uh , about why understanding story structures is useful skill for games developers
通常，这实际上是已经凭直觉完成的事情
And often it's actually something which is already done intuitively
这就是有趣的事情之一
So that's one of the interesting things about this
我要说的很多事情你都可以走了
That a lot of stuff that i'm gonna say you can go
哦，是的
Oh yeah
我们，我们已经做了一些这样的事情
We , we kind of already do some of that
这是我将其带入意识领域的一种方式
And it's a way of me moving that into kind of a conscious realm
我们可以看一个可靠的故事
We can look at a reliable stories
您可以使用的讲故事结构
Storytelling structure that you can use
这会帮助你讲故事，呃
Which will help you tell stories , uh
还有一些调试问题可以帮助您修复感觉无意义的故事或游戏玩法
And some debug questions to help you fix stories or game play that feels unrewarding
呃，在本次会议的最后、最后会有两张要点图
Uh , there's gonna be two takeaway diagrams at the very , very end of this session
所以当我在最后最后说了谢谢之后
So after i said thank you at the very , very end
有两张照片可以拍照
There are two pictures which you can take photo of
它会给你大量的总结
And it'll give you loads of summary
关于我今天所说的事情的信息
Information about the things i've been saying today
所以我们要讨论如何构建这些
so we're gonna talk about how to build those
并为您准备了一份美味的简单外卖
And a nice easy takeaway for you
如果你想在节目结束时拿起相机
If you want to bring up a camera right at the end of
这涉及很多内容
This is a lot to cover
所以我要说得很快
So i'm gonna be talking fast
关键点将出现在我身后的屏幕上
The key points are gonna be on the screen behind me
我有英国口音
I have an english accent
并非所有人都是以英语为母语的
Not all of you are native english speakers
呃
Uh
所以如果你不能，呃，就太容易跟随了
So if you can't , uh , follow too easily
如果你看屏幕
If you look at the screen
随着我们的进行，你会明白所有要点
you're gonna get all the main points as we go
那么让我们开始讨论一下流动游戏
So let's start off talking a little bit about flowing games
这是我们都明白的重要事情
This is something that we all understand is important
我们通常用图表来表达
We usually express this as a diagram
我们在金钱和技能方面面临挑战
Where we've got challenge on money and skill on the other
如果它是，呃，如果它的技能非常低
And if it's , uh , if it's got very low skill
呃，抱歉，下面的挑战对技能要求非常高
Uh , sorry , very high skill requirement below challenge
然后游戏就变得很无聊
Then game becomes quite boring
如果它的技能从低到低
And if it's got a low to low skill
但挑战太高，游戏变得太难
But high challenge and the game becomes too difficult
ERROR
It makes players really anxious
所以我们真的决定我们应该尝试并保持
So we decide really that we should try and keep
留人就是所谓的流量通道
Keep people what's called the flow channel
现在我们开始认为这是一条直线
Now we started off thinking that this was kind of a straight line
挑战和技能应该在彼此完美的关系中升级
That challenge and skills should escalate in perfect relationship to each other
但我们确实发现这更有趣
But we've discovered really that it's kind of more fun
如果是的话，如果我们沿着那里走的那种波浪形的摇摆线
If it , if this kind of wavy wobbly line that as we go along there
现在，如果你想了解更多关于心流的知识，这里有一些很棒的人
Now , if you want to learn more about flow there's some great people
你可以，呃，读一遍又一遍
You can , uh , read up on and over chan
杰西·谢尔给我哈雷六号发给我哈雷，呃
Jesse schell me harley six sends me harley , uh
他是那种想出了很多这样的东西的人，嗯
He was kind of guy who came up with a lot of this stuff , um
很难找到一个
Tricky one to search for
ERROR
Just go mahi and flow
它会出来油炸和谷歌，嗯
It will come out frying and google , um
这些人在 Flow 方面做出了惊人的工作
These people have done amazing work on flow
查一下
Look it up
现在当我们考虑讲故事时，呃，意图
Now when we think about storytelling , uh , intention
我们也可以用图表来表示
We also can express this as a diagram
而我们也经常这样做
And we often do so
我们经常在一侧感到紧张
We often have tension along one side
时间沿着故事的底部从零到百分之一百
And time going along the bottom there from zero to one hundred percent of our story
ERROR
And as we go through
我们有一些煽动事件
We have kind of the the inciting incident
第一个峰值是哪个
Which is that first peak
我们可以有一个低中点
We can have a low midpoint
事情出乎意料地变得更糟
Where things have got worse unexpectedly
当我们尝试修复它们时
When we tried to fix them
我们有最后的写作“黑色时刻”
We have that final what's called the black moment in writing
最大的黑暗时刻威胁着我们
Where there's kind of this moment of the greatest darkness threatens us
ERROR
And then we eventually overcome it
这是我们故事的结局
Which is the end of our story
现在实际上一般稍微多一点
Now it's actually generally slightly more
ERROR
Sort of nobly than that
我会解释为什么它有点多
And i'll explain why it's a bit more
比后来的还要高贵
Nobly than that in the later on
但正如你所看到的，当我们可以将这两个想法放在一起比较时
But as you can see , when we could kind of compare these two ideas together
我们看到，如果经过很多次，仍然有这个东西
we see that there's still this thing there that if a lot of times gone along
而且没有发生紧张，那就很无聊了
And no tension happened , then it's quite boring
它说，呃，非常紧张
And it says , uh , have really high tension
而且过去的次数并不多
And not a lot of times past
然后就感觉太紧张了
Then it feels too tense
感觉不自然
It doesn't feel natural
所以我们可以看到两者的切割组合
and so we can see there's kind of this cut combination of the two that
ERROR
We have these things that go in common between them
一
Um
但这种摇晃的线实际上代表什么
But really what does that kind of wobbly line actually represent
ERROR
What is this thing when we talk about games
这是什么，这是怎么回事？
What is , what is this thing going on here
现在当我们思考这个问题时
Now when we think about this
我们可以考虑一下你的游戏的故事是什么
We could think about what is the story of your game
现在我们可以走了
Now we can kind of go
ERROR
Well , your game has things that we might call pre authored content
这就是事件和内容之类的东西
So this is things like events and content
讲故事、、、、机制
The storytelling , the , the , the mechanics
它所在的世界
The world that it's in
这些是我们放入游戏中来讲述游戏故事的东西
These are things that we put into our games to tell the stories of them
另一方面，我们有我们的球员
On the other hand , we've got our players
太棒了，一大群人
Awesome , huge bunch of people
他们所有人都在玩这种东西，享受其中的乐趣
All of them playing , having fun with this kind of stuff
我们可以称其为用户生成的故事版本
We could call this a user generated version of the story
这就是他们与世界的互动
This is their interaction with the world
这是他们对世界的诠释
And it's their interpretation of the world
因为我们设计的世界可能不是他们看到的世界
Because the world that we design might not be the world that they see
因为他们根据自己玩游戏的经历和周围的世界对事物的解释不同
Because they interpret things differently based on their experiences are playing games and the world around them
所以在这两者之间
So between the two of these
我们可能会得到不同的东西
We might get different things
想象一下我们有一个世界，里面有一辆汽车在赛道上
So imagine we've got a world which has a car in it on a race track
而且它位于城市中心
And it's in the middle of a city
嗯，我们已经有了一个叙事背景
Well , we've already got a narrative setting there
我们了解汽车
We know about cars
我们了解城市
We know about cities
比赛开始了
And it starts off the race
在你和到达之间有这样的来回
And there's this back and forth between you and arrival
然后最后一个弯道即将到来
And then on the final bend is coming up
对手就在前面，最后一个角球响亮
And the rival is just ahead and loud final corner
竞争对手的驾驶技术不太好
The rival doesn't drive particularly well
你成功地把它带入了内心
And you managed to take it on the inside
奇妙的兴奋和可爱的小故事都可以浓缩在那一刻
Fantastic excitement and lovely little story can encapsulated in that moment there
这是游戏中的一个小故事
That's a tiny little story within a game
我们可以看到，我们是否考虑故事中的张力
And we can see that whether we think about tension in stories
或者我们是否将其视为流程
Or whether we think of this as flow
这基本上是一个故事
This is basically a story
这两行符合这里的经历
These these two lines fit with this experience over here
现在作为开发者
Now as as developers
我们通过人工智能塑造了它
We shaped that through the ai
也许我们在人工智能上做了橡皮筋，以确保我们的对手在最后一个弯道上很接近
Maybe we did rubber banding on the ai to make sure that that our opponent was close on that final bend
但愚蠢到我们刚经过那里就撞车了
But stupid enough to crash just as we were taking past it there
我们通过轨道设计对其进行了更改，以确保它很有趣
We changed it with a track design to make sure that it was fun
故事的节奏中会有令人兴奋的直角和弯角
That there was gonna be straight and corners that felt exciting and built in this rhythm of a story
他在哪里踢球
Where is he played
而从玩家的角度来看
And from a player's perspective
当他们运用自己的技能时
While they were using their skill
他们的选择
Their choices
他们控制弯道的方式为自己创造故事
Their their ways of controlling the corners to create that story for themselves
所以这两件事基本上创造了他们之间的玩家体验
So these two things have basically created the player experience between them
这条线
This line
他们创造的这个故事
This story that they've created
这条不稳定的线基本上就是这些之间的地方
This wobbly line is basically the the place between these
理想情况下，这就是我们作为游戏开发者所做的事情
And ideally that's the thing that we make as games developers
我们创造这种体验
We create that experience
我们为它创造空间
We create that space for it
我们帮助我们的用户实现这一点
And we help our users get to that point
那么我们如何做这种事情
So how do we do this kind of stuff
因此，流量理论认为，让玩家留在该流量通道中是件好事
So flow theory says that it's good to keep players in that flow channel
我们知道那是留住它们的好地方
We know that that's a good place to keep them
但我们如何做到这一点
But how do we do this
嗯，还有很多其他基于力学的想法
Well , there's lots of other ideas out there based on mechanics
但讲故事的人拥有结构化的系统，几千年来他们一直在可靠地使用这些系统来创造出色的观众体验
But storytellers have structured systems that they've been reliably using to create great your audience experiences for millennia
因此，与其重新发明轮子来理解玩家体验，不如
So rather than perhaps reinvent the wheel for understanding a player experience
我们可以从讲故事的人身上学到很多东西，了解他们如何塑造体验
We can learn a lot from storytellers in how they shape experiences
他们如何引导玩家的情感旅程
How they guide the emotional journey the players go on
所以我们要做的就是构建一个图表
So what we're gonna do here is gonna build in a diagram
其中涵盖了讲故事的基础知识
Which covers the basics of storytelling
我们将会有，呃，一些关于动机的小东西
We're gonna have , uh , some little bit of stuff about motivations
我们可以了解一些有关场景结构的东西
We can have some stuff about scene structure
很多事情都是从开始到结束的流程
And a lot of it is gonna be about a flow from beginning to end
大部分覆盖从百分之零到百分之一百，还有一点点
Mostly covering from zero to one hundred percent with a little bit more
最后还有一点
And a little bit at the end
整个图表将显示在这张幻灯片的最后
This whole diagram will be shown at the very , very end of this slide
所以不需要拍照
So you don't need to take photos
随着我们的进展逐步进行。顺便一提
Progressively as we go . by the way
除非你愿意
Unless you want to
呃
Uh
我还将填写一些有关每个时刻发生的情况的信息
And i'm also gonna be filling in some information about what happens at each juncture there
那么让我们开始讨论动机
So let's start off talking about motivations
这是讲好故事的关键部分
This is a really key part of of telling a good story
所以对于人物来说
So for characters
这些动机分为外部动机和内部动机
These are divided between external and internal motivations
外部动机是改变外部世界某些事物的愿望
An external motivation is the desire to change something in the world outside you
所以这往往是为了变得更富有
So this is often to get richer
从银行偷一些钱
To steal of some money from a bank
或者通过做某件事而变得富有和出名
Or become rich and famous through doing a particular thing
这是一种非常常见的外部动机
That's a a very common external motivation
它会改变你在外界的地位
It changes your status in the outside world
还有一个就是去旅行
Another one is to travel
你想要到达某个地方
You want to reach to a certain place
你想探索一个新领域
You want to explore a new area
作为你的改变
As a as a a change in your
呃，根据你所在位置的状态
Uh , status in terms of your location
建立友谊、爱情和人际关系正在改变你的关系状态
Forming friendships and love and relationships is changing your relationship status
这是在外界的一种状态
It's a status in the outside world
情绪在某些方面是一种内在的东西
Emotions are an internal thing in some ways
但它们如何影响外界仍然是外部动机
But how they affect the outside world is still an external motivation
例如，可能是和办公室里的帅哥约会
So it could be to date the hot guy in the office , for example
这可能是游戏的目标或你的角色的目标
That could be the objective of the game or for your character
所以就动机而言
So in terms of motivation here
内在动机是改变人内心某些事物的愿望
And internal motivation is a desire to change something inside the person
这通常被称为“征服一个省”
This is usually , uh , termed like overcoming a province
所以克服障碍
So overcome a block
这往往是情感障碍
It's often an emotional block
克服孤独感
Overcoming a sense of loneliness
克服悲伤
Overcoming , uh , grief
现在复仇是外在的事情，因为你影响了对外界的复仇
Now revenge is an external thing because you affect revenge on the outside world
克服悲伤是其中的内在部分
Overcoming grief is the inside part of that
你试图通过杀死外界的人来克服悲伤
You try to overcome grief by killing people in the outside world
这就是很多电子游戏情节的运作方式
That's how a lot of video game plots work
另一个内在动机是学习新东西
Another internal motivation is learning something new
通常这是他们应该已经知道的事情
Usually it's something they should have already known
你可以在一个方面成功，在另一个方面失败
And you can succeed in one and fail in the other
通常当你在外部激励方面取得成功而在内部激励方面失败时
And often when you succeed in external motivation and fail on internal motivation
你会看到一场悲剧，那就是罗密欧与朱丽叶
You get a tragedy that's romeo and juliet
两个家庭在尊严上是相似的
two families are alike in dignity
他们实际上从未接受过他们应该停止战斗的事实
who failed to actually ever come to terms with the fact that they should stop fighting
以及他们学习新东西的内在必要性
And their internal necessity to learn something new about themselves
ERROR
To learn that they're all the same to learn to accept their differences
如果他们不这样做就会杀死他们的孩子
And their failure to do that kills their children
这就是为什么这是一场悲剧
And that's why that's a tragedy
所以学习新东西是内部改变的一件大事
So learning something new is a huge thing of an internal change there
现在这两件事，就像我说的，都是关于改变的
Now both of these things , like i say they are about change
故事总是与变化有关
A story is always about change
一个改变。一个从头到尾没有变化的故事
A change . a story that doesn't have change from beginning to end
ERROR
Is a very , very boring story
现在可能只是你的角色拥有更大的枪
Now it can just be that your character got bigger guns
让我们换一种方式
Let's change of a kind
你知道
You know
而且效果很好
And it works pretty well
确实如此
It really does
呃
Uh
我知道我不会放弃游戏
I know i'm not putting down games
这纯粹是关于机械进步
Which is just purely about mechanic ical advancement
这也很有趣
That's a lot of fun as well
但我们还可以做其他事情来改变
But there are other things we can do to change
所以这种改变必须以某种方式发生
So that change must happen in some kind
但我们如何将所有这些东西应用到游戏中
But how do we apply all this kind of stuff to games
好吧，我们可能不认为托里亚斯是一款情节最精彩的游戏
Well , we might not think of torias a game with the greatest of plots
但它确实很好地遵循了这些事情
But it really does follow these kind of things pretty well
这是一种非常非常引人入胜的玩家体验
It's a very , very compelling player experience
现在如果我们考虑一下
Now if we think about this
如果我们考虑一下我们玩这个游戏时所经历的紧张弧线
If we think about kind of the tension arc that we go through when we're playing this
很适合那种流动的东西
It fits that flow thing
很合适。就是那个张力方舟
It fits . its that tension ark
玩家有外部目标和内部目标
And the player has both external , internal goals
我们将分数作为外部目标
We have the scores as an external goal
我们有这个内部目标
We have that internal goal
这是一种对秩序的渴望
Which is kind of a desire for order
俄罗斯方块的驱动因素是我们希望世界比实际情况稍微整洁一些
Tetris is driven by the thing that we like the world to be slightly neater than it is
这是一个很小的地方，也许
And this is a tiny place where maybe
也许会成功实现它
Just maybe will succeed in making it happen
而且总是悲剧
And it's always a tragedy
因为我们总是失败
Because we always fail
但我认为内部目标是俄罗斯方块持久吸引力的一个非常强大的部分
But i think that internal goal is a really powerful part of the lasting appeal of tetris
那种渴望秩序的感觉
That sense of desiring order
它总是从我们身边赶走
And it always chasing away from us
这是一次非常人性化的体验
That's a very human experience
我认为这就是它对我们具有持久吸引力的原因之一
And i think that's one of the reasons it works as such an enduring appeal for us
所以如果你快速将其添加到我们的图表中
So if you add that quickly into our diagram
那里有，呃，门
There we have the , uh , the door
动机是寻求改变
Motivation is a looking for change
通常表达这些非常直接的动词，例如保存和查找之类的东西
Usually express these very direct verbs like save and find and things like that
内部是关于克服或接受
and internal is about overcoming or coming to terms with
所以让我们继续讨论情节结构
so let's move on to plot structure
你已经为你的玩家角色设定了目标
You've got your goals for your player character
外部有内部动机
External internal motivations there
现在我们需要一个财富结构化的系列事件，通过这些事件将会发生变化
Now we need a wealth structured series events through which change will happen
外在的目标只是一个愿望
The external goals are just a desire
ERROR
We need the plot to make that change happen
所以，呃，情节控制着整个过程的进展速度
So , uh , a plot controls the speed of progress through the
穿越张力方舟的体验
Through the tension ark of the experience
所以我要更详细地讨论这个情节是如何运作的
And so i'm gonna be talking a little bit more in detail about how this plot works
所以在大事件开始之前开始你的故事
So start your story before the big events begin
这是很多游戏都未能正确做到的一件事
This is one thing that a lot of games fail to do properly
我的意思是，你不应该以你是巫师哈利开始你的故事吗？
By this i mean don't you don't start your story with you're a wizard harry
你和德斯利见面的整个部分
You you have this whole part of meeting the durslees
你有他的，他的童年
You have his , his childhood
他的，他在巫师世界之外的正常日常生活
His , his normal everyday life outside of the wizard world
在你来到这里之前，你会看到海格
Before you here you see the you see kind of hagrid
进来之前先体验一下魔法世界
Come in before you experience the world of magic
因为魔法世界本身毫无意义
Because the world of magic by itself means nothing
除非与平凡的世界形成对比
Unless it's contrasted by the world of the ordinary
我们有时会在游戏中看到这种情况
We see this sometimes in games
当我们这么做的时候，波斯王子就非常强大了
And when we do it's very powerful prince of persia
时间之声是我最喜欢的讲故事游戏之一
Sounds of time is one of my favorite storytelling games
一开始就有一些正常的片段
And there's got a little snatch of normality at the very beginning of it
真的很漂亮，很可爱的游戏
It's beautiful , really lovely game
所以你设置了你的角色
So you set up your character
二、本次活动的情况及基本规则
The situation and the basic rules of this
这也称为教程任务
This is otherwise known as a tutorial mission
你可以这样做
You can do it that way
你确实可以做到
It's you can literally do it
将其置于正常世界
Set it in a normal world
使命召唤有时会这样做
Call of duty sometimes does this
在你去射击之前你要在基地进行训练
That you train on the base before you go and shoot
意识形态上与你对立的人
People who are ideologically opposed to you
所以你
So you
我本来不想从事政治
I wasn't gonna do politics
我说我会的，嗯
I said i would , um
所以在事件开始之前就开始你的故事
So start your story before the events begin
如果可能的话，与你的角色建立同理心非常重要
It's really important to build empathy with your characters if possible
所以我们希望这个角色能够克服我们面前的挑战
So we wanted the character overcome the challenges ahead of us
啊，这真是一个很好的例子，我认为是看火人
Ah , really great example of this , i think is firewatch
我认为看火人在这方面做得很好
I think firewatch had done beautiful work with this
所以在我们到达看火湖之前
So before we reached the lake in firewatch
这才是故事真正开始、紧张气氛开始的时候
Which is really when the story begins to kick off and that tension starts
我们对哈利了解很多
We know a lot about harry
我们,我们知道他的外在内在动机
We , we know about his external internal motivations
故事从那一刻开始，他的外部动机真的被公园里的麻烦所激发
And the story begins with that moment there that his external motivation is really kicked off by there's trouble in this park
所以我们有了这些内部的东西
So we've got this internal stuff
需要逃避的成长
That growth that need to escape
我们知道在某个时候他将不得不回去
And we know at some point he's gonna have to go back
这是一个不错的设置
It's a nice setup
它使游戏的其余部分变得强大
And it makes the rest of the game powerful
如果我们从与少女的对抗开始
If we just started with that confrontation with the , the teenage women
呃，可能效果不太好
Uh , it probably wouldn't work so well
然后我们就发生了所谓的煽动事件
And then we have what we call the inciting incident
所以现在你是玩家角色，知道自己在世界上的位置
So now you're player character knows their place in the world
我们可以开始为他们设置挑战
We can start to set up the challenges for them
所以我们在这里增加叙事或机械张力
So we increase the narrative or mechanical tension here
我们给对手或敌人增加风险
And we add the antagonist or the enemies the risk
或者我们，我们打破了平常的情况，一些正常的事情
Or we , we break the usual situation , something which was normal
每一天都变得不那么正常
And every day becomes less normal
突然停止工作
Suddenly it stops working
看看斯坦利寓言中的内容
See it's in the stanley parable
按钮停止转动
The button stops going
克服这个问题通常是你情节的外部动机
Overcoming this problem is usually the external motivation of your plot
试图找到问题的根源并
Trying to find the source of that problem and
让一切恢复正常通常是主角的动力
And bring it back into normality is usually what drives your main character
但首先，尽管玩家角色回避了这个问题
But to begin with , though the player character avoids the problem
玩家通常不会直接解决问题
The player doesn't usually go straight to attacking the problem
他们要么探索自己的能力，要么探索世界
They'll either explore their abilities , explore the world
他们会避免面临的大问题
They'll avoid the big issues that's facing them
虽然一路上有一些较小的战斗
Although have some smaller battles along the way
所以在 vv , vv , vv , 呃
So in vv , vv , vv , uh
从现在开始我也称之为尖峰，呃
Which i also called spikes from now on , uh
所以在尖峰比赛中
So in spikes to play
角色必须拯救他们的同事
A character has to rescue their colleagues
这是一个非常可爱的小游戏
It's a really lovely little game
这让我想起了杰西说过的很多话
It reminds me a lot of jess said
威廉真是个可爱的小游戏。非常非常有趣
William is really a lovely little game . is very , very fun
但首先
But to begin with
基本上玩家会漫无目的地闲逛
Basically the player wanders aimlessly
真的，这就是你所做的
Really that's what you do
你不，你没有让你失望
You don't you're not set you off
我会立即找到大家
I shall find everybody immediately
现在你去玩吧，你就会看到世界上有什么样的谜题
Now you go off and play and you see what the kind of puzzles are in the world
经过一段时间的其他探索
Now after a little while other exploration
他们做出有意图的选择
They make a choice to act with intention
毕竟，这部剧给人的感觉是他们对这片土地足够了解，可以进行这场战斗
After all , the play feels like they know the territory enough to make that fight
集中选择行动
Focus choice to act
或者别无选择，只能行动
Or there's no choice left , but to act
您已完成所有提交
You've done all the submissions
你必须去看一个故事
you have to go to a story one
在尖峰中，这基本上意味着我最好更多地使用地图
In spikes , that means basically i'd better use the map more
如果你曾经玩过这个游戏，文斯
If you ever played the game , vince
你就走吧，是的
You kind of go , yeah
我迷路了
I'm lost
好的
Okay
这是什么闪烁的大象
What is this flashing elephant
一
Um
他们致力于实现外部目标
They engage with the external objective of the
他们面前的故事或世界
The story or the world that's ahead of them
那是他们真正开始涉足这个领域的时候
And that's when they really begin to kind of get into this
但当他们进一步深入时
But as they get further into it
复杂性开始增加
The complexity begins to increase
这些能力似乎，嗯，不太有效
The abilities seem , um , less effective
也许会添加新的敌人
Maybe new enemies are added
哪个伙伴，哪个更有挑战性
Which mate , which are more challenging
新的故事元素表明事情并非如此，是的
New story elements show that things were not so , yeah
并不像我们想象的那么简单
Not so simple as we thought they were to begin with
我认为俄罗斯方块是杰作
And i think tetris is a masterpiece
正是因为这一刻
Because of exactly this moment
复杂性突然增加
Suddenly complexity is increased
突然间我们知道前方将会有困难
And suddenly we know that there's going to be difficulty ahead
我们必须采取一种策略，将东西堆叠起来
and we're gonna have to a strategy of just piling things on top of each other
现在是一种将事情隐藏起来的策略
Is now a strategy of slipping things underneath
快要搬出去了
Just about quickly moved out
哦不
Oh no
突然间复杂性增加了
Suddenly the complexity is increased
这本身就是一个讲故事的时刻
And this is a storytelling moment in itself
我认为必须增加复杂性才能使体验引人注目
I think the complexity has to increase to make the experience compelling
否则它会停留在这种平坦的水平
Otherwise it stays at this kind of flat level
紧张的气氛没有改变
The tension doesn't change
这样复杂性就可以通过叙事术语而改变
So that complexity can change through narrative terms
机械术语，或通过两者
Mechanical terms , or through both
如果可以的话我两个都喜欢
I like both if you can
但你可以通过叙述来做到这一点
But you can just do it with narrative
我认为如果你制作纯粹的叙事游戏，这是一种非常有效的方法
I think that's a really valid way of doing it if you're making purely narrative games
所以在弗吉尼亚州，我们看到了主角之间的分歧
So in virginia , we see divisions between the protagonists
梦想开始对现实提出质疑
And the dreams begins to call some of reality into question
这是我们陷入火中的日常环境的复杂化
And this is a complexification of the everyday setting that we , we'd gone into in fire
观看额外的阴谋
Watching extra lay of conspiracy as added
公园里不仅有女性失踪，还发生了其他事情吗？
Is there's not just missing women there's some other stuff going on in the park
它会得到一点所有
And it will get a bit all
这很酷
It's cool
我喜欢我自己的游戏。他的碎片
I love the game in my own game . fragments of him
呃，威尔一直在努力建立一种、一种、一种长期的合作关系
Uh , will's kind of been trying to build a , a , a big long term relationship
读到一半他开始怀疑
And halfway through he begins to doubt
他能否在不伤害他人的情况下玷污一段关系
Whether he can stain a relationship without hurting other people
这是一个很大的疑问时刻
It's a big doubtful moment
这是，这是一种
And this is , this is kind of the
大多数故事的中低点
The , the , the low midpoint of most stories
所以最初的策略和武器已经不够了
So the first strategies and weapons are no longer enough
通常在射击游戏中，会添加新的敌人模式和组合
Usually in shooters , new patterns and combinations of enemies are added
呃，我认为超级巨星尘埃往往会在中途添加一些新东西
Uh , something i sua superstar dust tends to add a new things halfway through
敌人使用更好的瞄准更多子弹或追踪错过岛屿
Enemies use a better targeting more bullets or homing miss isles
敌人再次开始变得危险
Enemies again begin to kind of get dangerous
新能力，例如快速移动或在死亡时跟踪你
New abilities like moving fast or tracking you in left for dead
你不会把这些东西扔给玩家
You would not throw these things at the player
他们一走出门
As soon as they walk out the door
这很自然不是吗
It's just natural isn't it
这就是我的意思
And that's what i mean
ERROR
This , some of these patterns are intuitive to us
我们只知道这不是一个好主意
We just know it wouldn't be a good idea
然后希望战胜恐惧。经过一些努力
Then hope overcome fear . with some effort
ERROR
Player finds new weapons or strategies to overcome the enemies
外部变化发生
The external change happens
他们得到力量提升或磨练
They get power ups or grinding
这是一种，呃
This is kind of the , uh
电影中的武器蒙太奇和训练蒙太奇
The , the weapon montage and the training montage in a film
他们发现了他们从未意识到的力量
They find the strength they never knew they had
他们有内在改变的时刻
They have that moment of internal change
我认为生活很奇怪，凯特的故事做得很好
which i think life is strange does so well with kate's story
角色学会将他们的技能和团队团结起来实现一个目标
And the character learns to unite their skills and teams behind a single purpose
它有很高的风险
It has high risks
在这只是乐趣之前现在已经有危险了
There's danger ahead now before it was just fun
但现在面对这些事情有危险
But now there's danger in facing these things
但这是他们继续下去的唯一希望
But it is their only hope to continue
吉林看起来枪，很多枪
Guilling look guns , lots of guns
然后我们就到了至暗时刻
And then we get to the black moment
解决问题的所有希望都面临着风险
All hopes of overcoming the problem at a risk
最终boss被杀
The final boss is killed
但这还不是最终形式
But it's not even it's final form
我的天啊
Oh my god
正是在这种时刻，不断升级的危险显得太过分了
It's it's this kind of moment that the escalating danger seemed too much
以及所有的知识、关系
And all the knowledge , the relationships
通过玩家角色经验制定的策略
The strategies developed through the player character experience
我需要克服这最后的挑战
I needed to overcome this final challenge
最终的选择
The final choice
你一路上建立的令人心碎的关系
The heartbreaking relationships you've built along the way
现在所有人都处于危险之中
Are all at risk now
而对于未来你会做出怎样的选择
And what choice will you make about the future
这是一个强大的时刻
It's a powerful moment
黑色时刻
The black moment
在你的故事中非常非常重要
Very , very important in your story
然后你尽快结束它
And then you end it as fast as possible
人们常说，我的结局要到什么时候才会是你？
People often say , how long should my ending be you
所以你要尽快完成
So you do it as quickly as you possibly can
ERROR
And you keep the ending neat and short
尽可能多地包裹线程
Wrapping up as many of the threads as you possibly can
尽可能轻松地
As easily as you can
所以让我们将所有这些添加到我们的图表中
So let's add all of that to our diagram
好的
Okay
ERROR
So we're gonna start off with our before it begins moment
我们开始讨论煽动性事件
We get to our inciting incidents
我们需要改变的地方
Where we kind of have a need for change
但这个角色有点试图避免它
But the character kind of tries to avoid it
认为是别人的问题
Thinks it's somebody else's problem
然后他们就得到了外部目标的陈述
And then they kind of gets that statement of external objective
是的
Yes
我会勇敢地面对这一切
I will face up to this
是的
Yes
我会更多地使用地图并找到我的、我的同事
I will use the map more and find my , my colleagues
ERROR
They try this , uh
他们，他们尝试这些事情
They , they try these kind of things
然后它并没有真正起作用
Then it's not really working
我们到达低中点
We get to the low midpoint
ERROR
They're gonna have to get better
他们必须找到新的方法来处理这些事情
They're gonna have to find new ways of dealing with these kind of things
训练蒙太奇
Training montage
人们将通电
People going to power up
人们为了获得高尚的东西而更加努力地磨练他们的角色
People grind as their characters a little bit more to get their high things
我们在故事中看到了一些希望
We get some hope entering into the story
也许如果我继续这样做
Maybe if i keep on doing this
如果我在这个游戏中表现得更好
If i get better at this game
我会克服这些挑战
I'll overcome these challenges
ERROR
Let me get this this this moment of of of building up the the the body assembles behind this one plan
这将推动我们前进
Which is gonna push us forwar
当我们到了一切都处于危险之中的黑暗时刻
When we to the black moment where all is at risk
也许只要有足够的技能，有足够的我们一路上保存下来的东西
And maybe just with enough skill , with enough of the things that we saved along the way
我们可以克服
We can overcome
我们得到了最终令人满意的结论
And we have the final satisfying conclusion
凉爽的
Cool
您可能已经注意到结尾处缺少一些内容
you may have noticed there's a bits missing at the beginning of the end there
因为这是大多数故事作为玩家角色旅程的模型
Because that's a model for most stories as a player character journey
这适合最强烈的体验
This fits most strong experiences
ERROR
A lot of films you see will follow this model pretty much exactly
它在直觉和情感层面上发挥作用，让人感觉非常有价值
It works on an intuitive and emotional level to feel very rewarding
但如果你要拍惊悚片
But if you're making a thriller
真实或恐怖的故事
An actual or horror story
ERROR
You might want to add an extra little bit on there horror stories in particular
做这个有一个额外的结构
Do this one there's an additional bit of structure
您可能需要考虑在一开始就添加
You might want to consider adding at the very beginning
这就是所谓的抓取器
Which is called the grabber
这是一种行动恐惧的爆发，预示着游戏的未来
It's a burst of actional fear that promises for future of the game
并在煽动事件发生前放慢速度
And slows down before the inciting incident
所以这是让玩家角色知道前方将会有令人兴奋的事情的一种方式
So it's a way to let the player character know there's gonna be excitement ahead
然后你稍后给他们一点喘息的空间
And then you give them a bit of breathing space later on
例如
For example
这是一款银河战士游戏，一开始你就会拥有大量强大的力量
This is the metroid games where you end up with loads of great powers at the beginning
ERROR
And then they take them away and kind of go
好的
Okay
现在让你慢慢建立起来
Let's let you build those up slowly now
或者呃，火焰杯
Or the uh , goblet of fire
一开始就有恐怖的时刻
It gets moment of horror at the beginning
你知道，稍后还会有另一个恐怖时刻
And you know , it's gonna have another moment of horror later on
果然，最后一名少年被冷血杀害
And sure enough , a teenager is killed in cold blood at the very end
这是剧透
That's a spoilers
抱歉，呃
Sorry , uh
但这就是它，这是一种告诉我们将会有事情发生的方式
But it's it's it's , it's a way of telling us that there's gonna be something coming along
日间性爱从一开始就用所有的能力做到这一点
Day sex does this with with all the abilities at the beginning
之后稍微拿走一些较慢的粘贴
Take some away slower paste a bit after that
星际迷航 .杰·艾布拉姆斯
Star trek . jj abrams
你已经死了
You've got death
你有爱
You've got love
你已经出生了
You've got birth
你有牺牲
You've got sacrifice
你有很棒的东西
You've got amazing stuff
不是电影的前五分钟
Not the first five minutes of the film
嗯，真的，我jj艾布拉姆斯是抓取大师
Um , really , i jj abrams is a master of the grabber
我认为这是一件非常重要的事情
It's a very important thing , i think
但如果你能在恐怖故事中做这种事
But if you can do that kind of stuff in horror stories
最后你常常也会有最后的恐惧时刻
You often also have a final moment of fear at the end
潜伏着所谓的邪恶
Which called evil lurks
当当当
Dang dang dang
所以在《嘉莉》中，这就是手从地下伸出来的时候
So in carrie , this is when the the hand comes up from the beneath the the earth
还抢她这种东西
And grabs her this kind of thing
这是租金期限结束时的噩梦
It's the nightmares at the end of a rent horizon
但有时你也会感到兴奋
But also you sometimes have this in thrills
该组织也许还没有完全失败
Where the organization perhaps wasn't quite defeated
ERROR
So in austin powers dr
邪恶逃脱
Evil escapes
您知道，这是我们使用的一种相当常见的结构
You know , this is a fairly common kind of structure that we do with this
或者杀戮地带的尽头
Or the end of kills zone too
你杀了大老板的地方
Where you've killed the big boss
我的天啊
Oh my god
太棒了
It's brilliant
战争结束了，你走到外面，战争仍在继续
The war is over , you walk outside and the war is still going
哦，看起来很邪恶，他们会在三点被杀
oh evil looks they'll be killed on three
所以我们只需将它们快速添加到该结构的末尾的开头即可。开始了
so we just add those quickly at the beginning of the end of that structure . here we go
到目前为止我们已经描述了这一点
So we've described this so far
这里有这条漂亮的平滑曲线
This nice smooth curve in here
该图很好地解释了玩家角色的旅程
The diagram explains the player character journey pretty nicely
，呃，它可以从字面上应用来帮助编写游戏中的故事
the , uh , it could be applied literally to help write an in game story
或者作为一种隐喻结构，在引人注目的机械驱动体验中塑造张力
Or as a metaphorical structure to shape tension in a compelling mechanics driven experience
无论你想用哪种方式来做
Whichever way you want to do it
这种结构以情感方式发挥作用
This kind of structure works on an emotional way
所以我们也可以这样设置
So we can also sort of set it out like this
ERROR
This model works is a metastructure for the entire game
但你也可以在较小的层面上做到这一点
But it also you can do it on a smaller level
它可以逐级重复
It can repeat on a level by level basis
呃，随着关卡的一点点
Uh , with each little bit of the level
有助于某种，呃，通往外部内部动机的旅程
Contributing to kind of the , uh , journey towards that external internal motivation
呃，这就是我在《外星人与掠夺者》中所做的，例如
Uh , this is what i did on aliens versus predator , for example
每个级别都有一个完整的故事
Every level of that has a full story inside it
以及为游戏的完整故事做出贡献
As well as contributing to the full story of the game
但这对于每个遭遇或场景来说细节太多了
But that's too much detail for each encounter or scene
所以如果你想创造一个好的场景，就用它来工作
So if you want to make a good scene to be to , to work with that
为此我们需要一个简单一点的指南
We need a little , little simpler sher guide for that
基本上，我们想把它变成那种高贵的版本
Basically , we want to turn this into that kind of nobly version
那么我们该如何去做呢
So how do we go about doing this
好吧，我们用场景结构来做到这一点
Well , we do this with scene structure
这是该图的最后一部分
It's the final part of that diagram
我们要在那里添加
We're gonna add in there
所以你所在关卡中的所有场景都必须有一个目标
So all scenes on your level must have an objective
这是玩家的目标或经验
Which is the player's target goal or experience
你必须有冲突，一些能够实现目标的东西
You must have conflict , something that makes the objective
更难到达，就像，呃
More difficult to reach it's like , uh
这可以是叙述性的，也可以是机制性的，或者两者兼而有之
This can be either nnarrative or mechanics or both
某种让我们挣扎的冲突
Some sort of conflict that makes us struggle
让我们更难实现这些事情
Makes it harder for us to make these things happen
然后通过要求角色玩家做出改变来达到结果
And then outcome is reached by requiring change from the player of the character
所以他们要么解决冲突，要么适应冲突
So they either resolve or adapt to the conflict
构建故事体验的下一部分
Building to the next part of the experience of the story
故事随着那里的紧张局势不断升级而继续下去
And the story goes on with escalating tension there
你会得到这些漂亮的小峰
And you get these nice little peaks of
哦，我会成功的
Oh i'm gonna make it
哦，不，这并不更令人期待
Oh no , that wasn't more expected
哦，我是
Oh i am
你会得到这些小张力方舟
You get these little tension arks coming all
一路走来都有
All the way along the way there
这是《外星人大战》中的联盟角色
So this was the league character from aliens vs
掠食者或这方面的作家
Predator or a writer on this one
呃，你的首要目标之一就是重置殖民地
Uh , one of the first objectives you get is to reset the , the colony
呃，权力，让它发挥作用。再次
Uh , powers to , to make it work . again
冲突就是力量
The conflict is the power
pler成功重置断电
The pler successfully resets the cut power
ERROR
But it blows the circuits across the colony
所以之前殖民地实际上面临的风险更大
So the colony is actually more at risk before
而且人物的生活也更加复杂
And the character's life is more complex
现在请注意，玩家成功了，而角色失败了
Now notice here that the player succeeded whilst the character failed
所以只要你有路标，你仍然可以获得玩家的成功
So you can still have player success as long as you signpost
干得好，你做对了
Well done , you've done the right thing
你的玩家的生活现在更糟糕了，但没关系
Your player's life now sucks even more that's perfectly fine
事实上，我强烈鼓励您尽可能多地这样做
In fact , i thoroughly encourage you to do that as often as possible
因为如果你的角色的生活很轻松
Because if your character's life is easy
他们，他们的故事通常很无聊
Their , their story is usually pretty boring
所以尽可能多地尝试玩这种东西
So try and play with this kind of stuff as much as you can
所以另一个例子可能是上帝
So another example for this might be the god
可能是战神系列
Might be god of war series
目标是继续杀死一切
Where the objective is to continue killing everything
呃
Uh
然后你就有了冲突
And then you have the conflict
谁用盾牌对付敌人
Which is who gets enemies with shields
阻止通常的攻击
Which block the usual attacks
所以玩家必须开始使用新的攻击才能进步
And so the player has to start using new attacks to progress
让游戏更具挑战性
Making the game more challenging
玩家的复杂性增加
The complexity increases for the player
没有改变的性格
The character that has not changed
这个角色只是想让他们杀死一切
The character just wants to keep them killing everything
所以在这里我们再次看到我们有
So here we see again that we've got
我们在场景中不断升级的小便控制
We've got that escalating little pee control in a scene
但这一次对于玩家的复杂性来说却是相反的
But it's working the other way around for the , for the players complexity this time
所以让我们在其中添加它
So let's add that in there
所以我们有我们的目标
So we have our objective
我们有我们的冲突，我们有我们的结果
We have our conflict and we have our outcome
这将出现在最后的幻灯片上
This will be on the final slides
你不需要去思考
You don't need to go think
我现在就要改变它，已经太晚了
And i'm gonna change it now ha too late
一
um
游戏就是玩家的故事
For games are players stories
所以如果你的游戏感觉平淡
So if your game feels flat
然后将你的、你的玩家体验视为一个故事，这是调试它的好方法
Then think of your , your players experience as a story is a good way of debugging it
想想他们正在经历的事情
Think about what they're experiencing as they going through it
所以这里有四个调试问题要问
So here are four debug questions to ask
呃，在游戏、事件或关卡中感觉令人满意
The , uh , in a game , event or level feels on satisfying
我也会在最后放一张图表
And i'm gonna put a diagram of this at the very end as well
好的
Okay
呃，这个地方目标明确吗？
Uh , is the place objective clear
是否存在不断升级的机械或叙事冲突
Is there an escalating mechanical or narrative conflict
或者只是重复
Or is it only repetition
我们以前做过吗
Have we done this before
结果是否对机制、叙事或两者都有有意义的补充
does the outcome meaningfully add to the mechanics , the narrative or both
整场比赛就是他们从开始到结束的变化
And over the whole game was their change from start to finish
对于玩家、角色或两者
For the player , the character or both
这种改变是非常关键的事情
That change is a really key thing
让你的游戏体验感觉良好，真的很重要
To making your game experience feel good , really really important thing
所以这件事就这样结束了
So it's gonna conclude this
现在结束这一切
Wrapping this all up now
好的设计已经被直观地使用了
Good design is already intuitively used
因此故事结构可以创造引人入胜且有益的游戏
So story structures to create compelling and rewarding games
尽管我认为有意识地学习是一种强有力的理解方式
Learning to do so consciously though i think is a powerful way of understanding
我们如何有意识地利用故事塑造美好体验
How we shape great experiences using stories consciously
了解人们所经历的紧张局势
Understanding this tension ark that people go through
这是波峰和波谷
That it is peaks and troughs
不是一条直线是一件非常重要的事情
Not a straight line is a really important thing to do
因此，无论您的游戏是叙事性的还是机制性的
So whether your game is narrative or mechanics oriented
学习像讲故事的人一样思考可以帮助您做出明智的以玩家为中心的设计选择
Learning to think like a storyteller helps you make intelligent player focus design choices
我希望您觉得这次演讲有趣且有用
I hope you found this talk interesting and useful
如果您想了解更多，请联系我们，呃
Getting in touch if you want to know more , uh
请在会议结束后发表评论并进行审查
Please leave comments with review after the session
我确实阅读了你在那里发表的所有评论
I do read all the comments you put in there
那些太棒了
Those are awesome
所以我将在下一张幻灯片后展示这两张图
So i'm gonna show those two diagrams after the next slide
所以我要说一声谢谢
So i'm going to say thank you one
然后我将展示这两个图
Then i'll show the two diagrams
我们都可以拍照片之类的东西
And we can all take photos and stuff like that
一
Um
在那之前我想说玩得开心
Before that i wanted to say have fun
制作精彩的游戏并讲述一些精彩的故事
Make great games and please tell some great stories
非常感谢您的聆听
And thank you so much for listening
二十九分十五秒
Twenty nine minutes , fifteen seconds
哇！哈哈哈
Wow ! ha ha ha
谢谢你对的
thank you right
让我们来做吧
Let's do
让我们做一下相机部分
Let's do the camera bit
我们到这里
here we go here
我喜欢这个
I love this fi
看到大约有两百个摄像机出现，太棒了
see about two hundred cameras come up it's great
哈哈哈哈
Ha ha ha ha
我应该拿出相机给你拍张照片
I should get my camera out and take photo of you
大家
Everybody
他刚刚拍了一张照片
He just took a photo
将相机举在空中
Hold a camera in the air
惊人的
Awesome
谢谢
Thank you
呃，好吧，我们开始吧
Uh , okay , let's do
我们来做下一个
Let's do the next one
我们去吧
There we go
一些关于使用的 cd 错误问题可以帮助你解决这个问题
Some cd bugging questions for uses help you through there
关于如何使用它们的一些提示
Some tips about how to use them
什么样的事情可能会给你带来问题
Kind of , what sort of things are probably causing you problems
如果你必须这样做，呃，如果你自己没有得到这些问题的好的答案
If you have to , uh , if you don't get a good answer to those questions for yourself
凉爽的
Cool
好的
Okay
我们有时间提问还是必须现在就结束
Do we have time for questions or do we have to wrap up right now
我想我们可能得结束了
I think we probably have to wrap up
有一个包房
There is a wrap up room
这是二二二
Which is two o two two
我想他们说的是二二二
I think they said two o two two
这是正确的吗
Is that correct
这是正确的
It is correct
出色的
Excellent
大家
Everybody
非常感谢你们来到这里
So thank you so , so much for being here
我希望你喜欢这次演讲
I hope you enjoyed that talk
再次感谢您
Thank you once again
谢谢
Thank you